<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lesson learned | ]]></title>
  <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/categories/lesson-learned/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-20T00:06:41-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family and Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/11/09/family-and-work"/>
    <updated>2011-11-09T21:09:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/11/09/family-and-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently friends on Facebook start sharing a picture, "shortest speech by CEO of Coca Cola":</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p><img height="364" width="494" alt="f" src="/images/blog/2011-11-10-family-and-work-0.jpg" /></p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>It turns out I've read a similar article before: "<a target="_blank" href="http://adamschepis.com/blog/2011/09/15/why-i-go-home-a-dads-manifesto/">Why I Go Home: A Developer Dad’s Manifesto</a>", specifically, </p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<blockquote>&#13;
<p><span>For me this came down to priorities and a simple realization: If you screw up at your job you can always get another one, but if you screw up your family, especially your relationship with your children, it will stay with you and stay screwed up forever.</span></p>&#13;
</blockquote>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p><span>I agree with them.</span></p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[悟]]></title>
    <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/11/08/12548148932"/>
    <updated>2011-11-08T21:53:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/11/08/12548148932</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这么一篇blog，其实写起来很蛋痛。就这么简单的道理，要洋洋洒洒这么多字么？我无法回答这个问题。我的blog，就是记录我的所感所想，无论大小。</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>我就一直没明白一个事情: 为什么Ralphs卖的烤鸡味道就这么淡？</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>有的时候自己不想做肉吃，就去Ralphs 买那种烤好的鸡来吃。方便是方便但是味道真的很淡。除了外面的皮，里面的白肉就没什么味。”这么没味，应该很有营养吧“ 每次我都是这么欺骗我自己吃下去的。我就不明白外国人怎么就能吃得下去。难道是我平时辣椒吃太多口味太重了？</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>今天我突然知道原因了。</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>中午我在吃蔬菜沙拉，带了一点鸡肉，白的。吃得时候竟然觉得味道刚好，一点都不淡。顿悟道：原来味道浓淡是看跟什么比了。以前我都是自己炒的菜配上鸡肉。自己炒的菜盐肯定放得不少，辣椒肯定下得够狠。这时候吃鸡肉当然觉得淡了。外国人沙拉之类的吃得多，加上他们做的东西也没这么多配料，我觉得淡味的鸡肉他们自然也就觉得还不错了。</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>小时候看电视经常问爸妈，谁是好人谁是坏人。依稀记得他们总会“勉强得”给我个答案。现在知道，好坏，其实是相对的。</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>生活也是这样，幸福不幸福，开心不开心，都是相对的，就是看你跟什么比了。不管是有意识的还是无意识的，大脑做出的各种形容词的结论，就是比较后的结果。不开心时，肯定是比较的东西太高了。要么把比较的东西放低点; 要么朝着高高在上的那个东西而努力。就这么简单。人生苦短，开心就好。</p>


<p>&#13;
&#13;</p>

<p>PS: 后来在网上看到这篇"<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cnblogs.com/jtf-china/archive/2011/09/11/2173710.html">年轻人, 你着什么急?</a>"，意思差不多，写得比我好多了。大家可以去看下。</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lesson Learned: as a good programmer, you should have faith in your own code]]></title>
    <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/10/18/lesson-learned-as-a-good-programmer-you-should-have"/>
    <updated>2011-10-18T21:12:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/10/18/lesson-learned-as-a-good-programmer-you-should-have</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the first day that I'm little bit pissed off at work. I was doing a data parser for a file format outside our company. I've done similar things and I thought it could be easy. And it turned out the data I parsed was wrong. Then I asked questions to the file format owner. The file format owner was too busy on other things to answer my question directly. The answers I got all the afternoon were NOT on the point: either things too easy like "this is the C/C++ cast that I don't know does .Net has it or not", or things too complex and should not be concerned like "different compiler might pad uncertain data for data byte alignments". And finally the owner replied me like this: "oh here is the latest spec, it turns out the spec you have is not up to date and your code missed those dummy bytes". I knew I was right. I was too conservative to say it's not my code but the spec I had was wrong.</p>


<p>&#13;
&#13;</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: as a good programmer, you should have faith in your own code.</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the waist down]]></title>
    <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/09/08/from-the-waist-down"/>
    <updated>2011-09-08T23:53:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2011/09/08/from-the-waist-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to believe, but from waist down, my muscle sucks. I mean, <strong>real</strong> muscle.</p>


<p>&#13;
&#13;</p>

<p>My thigh gets really sore after 30 squat jumps, my calf muscle is really complaining after jumping rope for 80 turns...</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>Muscles from waist up, on the other hand, is way better.</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>The reason?</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>- I sit in front of the computer for a loooooong time every day. Lower body seldom moves.</p>


<p>&#13;
&#13;</p>

<p>The solution?</p>


<p>&#13;</p>

<p>- Watch Wall-E, and decide go hiking, running, or walking. </p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lesson Learned: Call Your Credit Card Company]]></title>
    <link href="http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2010/05/10/lesson-learned-call-your-credit-card-company"/>
    <updated>2010-05-10T20:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://hamxiaoz.github.com/blog/2010/05/10/lesson-learned-call-your-credit-card-company</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I found out I was late on my credit card and there were late fee $39 and purchase interest fee $13 posted on my account already. $52 bucks is not big but definitely not small. It almost costs as much as my favorite game FIFA WC 2010. Given that I&rsquo;ve spent such amount of bones on the game, I decided to take it back. I called the 888 number.</p>

<p>A guy with a machine voice picked up my call. I said &ldquo;Hello??&rdquo; twice to make sure it&rsquo;s a human being on the other end. First I asked why I got those fees, pretending I was innocent. Then the &ldquo;machine&rdquo; guy explained it pretty well, well enough to make me doubt myself why I&rsquo;m making this stupid call. I was kind of shy at that time, but finally, I asked,</p>

<blockquote><p>- &ldquo;Can you waive the interest fee? Or even the late fee?&rdquo;  (shyness…)<br/>
- &ldquo;Since this is the first time you&rsquo;re late, I can waive the fee. But I can only waive either one of two, which one would you like me to waive&rdquo;?  (actually, this is NOT the first time I&rsquo;m late… But I know, people do things for good cause)<br/>
- &ldquo;En… how about the late fee?&rdquo; (cause it&rsquo;s $39!!)<br/>
- &ldquo;Ok, you&rsquo;ll see $39 back on your next statement."<br/>
- @#!~<em>&amp;</em> (connection was bad, and my iPhone showed "Call Failed&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>

<p>To my surprise, it was easy to get my money back. But it was not clear that he said so. So I called back again. This time it was a nice and probably young guy. I felt I should go straight to the point, and I did that. The young guy gave me positive confirmation. Ok, good, mission completed. Wait, how about the $13 interest fee? Then I made bold  to [斗胆] ask:</p>

<blockquote><p>- &ldquo;Can I also get the interest fee back?"<br/>
- (me again) "You know, I always pay my card on time, and this is actually the first time I see the interest fee."<br/>
- "Ok, I&rsquo;ll waive the fee.. blah blah&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>To my surprise again, it was easy to get the interest fee back. I&rsquo;m feeling good now, not because I get the money back, but also there is a Lesson Learned:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Next time you get charged for a fee on your credit card, do NOT email or feel bad, call them and ask for the money back.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Be brave.</strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
